Breaking off a noble's wedding
闯进贵族之间的婚礼…
is punishable by death.
会被处死的
You must be quite foolish
竟然做这种蠢事 你真的太蠢了
Stop calling me foolish, you foolish woman.
别一直说我蠢 你这蠢女人
There is no need for you to take on the responsibility of paying off my debts!
不要擅自代替我还债啦
Think you are my wife?
你以为自己是我的老婆吗
Didn't I tell you to just be honest if you have feelings for me?
我不是说过喜欢我的话就老实说吗
I never said that!
谁说过那种话啊
You fool!
你这个大笨蛋
(Episode 11: Blessings for the Unchanging Daily Life) Who does this lowly pauper think they are, daring to be so arrogant?
(第11集 为不变的日常献上祝福) 区区一个穷人还敢嚣张
Lalatina owes me two billion, you know.
拉拉蒂娜欠了我20亿哦
If you want her, bring the money,
如果想要这个女人就拿钱来
assuming you have it.
前提是你有钱的话
You know, a true gentleman always keeps his promises.
男子汉可不能出尔反尔哦
Say what?
你说什么
Here's the two billion that Darkness borrowed.
达克妮丝借的20亿
Now I can bring her along.
这样我就能带走达克妮丝了
T-Two billion?
2…20亿?
M-My money.
我…我的钱
-Hey, that's my money! -Money, it's money…
-喂 那可是我的钱 -钱 是钱…
Hey, you people!
喂 你们这些人
That's my money!
那可是我的钱
This money… Where did this money come from?
这些钱…这些钱是从哪里来的
I sold them.
我卖了
I managed to sell off all the knowledge and rights I could think of,
我把想到的知识和权利全卖了
along with the bounty I had saved up from before,
再加上之前存下来的讨伐奖金
and it ended up totaling a cool two billion Eris.
正好是20亿艾莉丝
No way.
不会吧
You…
你这个人…
You really are…
你这个人真是…
You can't say no.
你没有拒绝的权利
Listen. Starting now, I am going to have complete control over you.
听好了 今后我会狠狠奴役你
You will have to repay the money I spent with your body.
我花掉的钱 就用你的身体来还
Get ready for it.
给我做好觉悟
Do you get it, you twisted cross knight!
听懂没 你这个大变态十字骑士
Answer me if you get it!
听懂的话就回答我
Yes!
好
Those words just now
刚刚那些话
felt like a direct hit to a masochist.
好像对被虐狂是会心一击
Why are you holding me back when it matters?
为什么要在关键的时候 像这样扯我后腿啊
Don't take my money!
你们不要随便拿
That hurts!
好痛
To ask me to pay back with my body
居然叫我用身体来还
and even carry me like a princess…
而且还公主抱
Hey, you're drooling.
喂 你流口水了
Just like always, Mr. Kazuma is truly despicable.
不愧是猪狗不如的和真先生
Despicable?
猪狗不如?
You are paying back the debt she took on for you,
明明只是还她替你背的欠债
but for some reason, you make it seem like you are purchasing her.
不知为何却像是买下达克妮丝
I am asking her to work hard
我的意思是叫她作为冒险者
to gain money as an adventurer.
努力工作赚钱啦
M-Mr. Kazuma.
和…和真先生
Get down and walk by yourself!
喂 你快下来自己走啦
You have got quite the muscles, so you are quite the heavyweight!
你肌肉很多所以超重的
Do not call me a heavyweight!
不准说我重
I've seen it all now.
我已经全都看开了
Get out of my path, ye scum of the earth!
领主的走狗们 给我让开
If you do not step aside,
如果不肯让开
I will harm you!
我就宰了你们
I don't understand why you are going in there all by yourself!
喂 你自己冲进去是要怎么办啊
Aqua, support!
阿库娅 支援
Cast support magic on me!
帮我施展支援魔法
Yeah!
包在我身上
Do you need the Master of Talent magic?
需要变成才艺高手的魔法吗
It hurts!
好痛…
It's going to split open, it's going to split open!
要裂开了 要裂开了
You guys!
你们
Forget about her, come over here quickly!
别管她了 快过来这边
Help me pick up the money.
帮我捡钱吧
Yes, sir!
是 遵命
Very well.
很好
Lord Aldarp.
阿尔达普大人
Why are you all here?
你们在做什么啊
Hurry up and catch Lalatina!
快点去抓拉拉蒂娜
Very well.
很好
In this rate…
就这样…
I will not allow you to go.
我…不能让你们过去
So big!
好大
Stop there!
站住
Holy cow. We are running out of options.
喂 我们走投无路了
What should we do?
该怎么办
Any ideas on what we should do?
你们说该怎么办啊
Light of Saber!
Light of Saber
Megumin, it worked!
惠惠 成功了
I have managed to do it!
我成功做到了
If it is a request from a close friend,
如…如果是好朋友的请求
I'm willing to do something that could be considered questionable.
要我做这种类似犯罪的事也没关系
Yeah, yeah.
好好
You truly are my close friend.
不愧是我的好朋友
The wicked magician has shown up.
邪恶的魔法师来了
I went with my gut
我遵从本能
and came to take the bride away.
来拐走新娘了
She has been throwing around Explosion in the town!
她开始在市区施展爆裂魔法了
That's the crazy…
那是脑袋有问题的…
There is no way that light could be Explosion, could there?
那个光该不会是爆裂魔法吧
H-Huh?
奇…奇怪
Megumin, Mr. Kazuma…
我说惠惠 和真先生已经…
She must be faking.
肯定是在虚张声势
Do you know the implications of casting that kind of spell here?
你知道在这种地方施展 会有什么下场吗
Hurry up and catch her!
快点抓住她
Oh, you think I'd be scared?
哦 你以为我会害怕吗
Scared of casting Explosion?
害怕施展爆裂魔法
Alright, alright.
好吧 好吧
I accept your challenge.
我就接受你的挑战吧
Stop it!
住手
We won't come any closer, so stop it!
我们不会接近你 快住手
Lord Aldarp, please do not provoke her!
阿尔达普大人 请您不要挑衅
You took away my moment of glory.
居然抢走我的锋头
I didn't expect you to beat me to it.
没想到被你抢先了
Megumin, and Yunyun.
惠惠 还有芸芸也来了
I will…
回去后…
I will thank you once we get back.
回去后我会答谢你们
Um…
那个…
Aren't we companions?
我们不是伙伴吗
I will not let a fine cross knight quit our squad that simply.
我不会让优秀的十字骑士 轻易离开的
Hey, you onlookers over there!
喂 那边的围观者
You, who appear to be adventurers,
外表看起来像冒险者的你们
bring my bride back for me!
把我的新娘抢回来
I will give you a nice reward.
我会给你们丰厚的酬劳
How much do you want?
你们想要多少
Did you hear that?
有听到吗
You can get rid of the just-getting-by life.
你们可以摆脱 那种得过且过的生活哦
Hey, come play soccer!
喂 来踢足球吧
Very well.
很好
Hey, pass the ball!
嘿 传球传球
Pass it here, pass it here!
传过来 传过来
Come on.
来…来吧
Wha--
什…
Everyone wants to help you.
大家都想帮你
Get over your intransigence, give it some serious thought.
改改你那个死脑筋 好好反省吧
It's wonderful.
真美好
Lord Aldarp.
阿尔达普大人
Finally arrived.
终于来了吗
This is bad.
糟糕
Hurry, get out of here!
快逃吧
K-Kazuma.
和…和真
I can't keep it up any longer.
我没办法继续维持了
May I cast it now?
我可以施展了吗
N-No, you can't.
不…不行啦
You can't cast it here.
不能在这种地方施展
I can't hold out any longer.
我撑不住了
No, no, no. You can still hold on, right?
不不不 你还撑得住吧
You are capable of accomplishing anything you set your mind to.
你是有心就能做到的人
Let go slowly, like that.
就这样慢慢地 慢慢地放开吧
Good girl, you can't give up, okay?
乖乖 不能放弃哦
I can't do it anymore.
不行了
-Everyone, quickly get away from me! -Can't you?
-大家快点离开我 -不行吗
Run!
快逃啊
Explosion!
爆裂魔法
Alright. Why not go now?
好了 趁现在…快走?
Hey.
我说你
It is really disappointing to see someone hiding
躲在自己来救的对象后面也太…
behind the person they are supposed to save.
太差劲了
-You are awful, Mr. Kazuma. -I'm Kazuma.
-和…和真先生好差劲 -我是和真
They are going to flee!
他们要逃走了
She can no longer use Explosion.
她无法再施展爆裂魔法了
Quickly catch them!
快抓住他们
Mr. Kazuma, Mr. Kazuma.
和真先生 和真先生
Aqua?
阿库娅?
That hurts!
好痛
A sudden force pushed me down!
我突然被推倒了
Fracture. I have a fracture.
骨折…我骨折了
Dust, save me!
达斯特 救救我
Hey, Keith.
喂 奇斯
This is just too awful.
真是太惨了
He's got a comminuted fracture in his arm.
他的手臂粉碎性骨折了
Who cares?
谁管你们啊
Wha--
什…
Hey, let go of me.
喂 放开我
Did you not say it was a fracture? How come you can still grab it?
不是说骨折了 为什么还能抓住
Hey, hey, hey!
喂喂喂
You have rendered my dearest friend immobile,
你害我的死党半身不遂
and you have not even expressed regret?
却连一句道歉都没有吗
You are really pulling off the big shot, right?
真会耍大牌呢
You mentioned that there was a fracture,
你明明说他是手臂骨折
at what point did it become immobile?
什么时候变成半身不遂了
Give me a break.
给我适可而止
That hurts!
好痛
He attacked me!
他对我施暴了
They are taking advantage of their privileges!
喂 他们滥用特权
Don't underestimate adventurers!
不要小看冒险者
I have been dealing with some difficult nobles lately,
最近贵族让我吃了苦头
so I might just vent my frustration on you.
我要拿你们泄愤
Let us treat them to some bubble wine later.
之后再请他们喝泡泡酒吧
My bride!
我的新娘
Don't go, don't go, Lalatina!
别走 别走 拉拉蒂娜
You are…
你是…
Excuse me.
我进来了
So beautiful.
真美
Just like your mother.
就像你妈妈一样
I'm sorry.
对不起
I opted to marry on my own
我擅自决定结婚
and ended up ruining everything.
却以最坏的结果毁了
I see.
这样啊…
Kazuma.
和真
I will walk outside to get some fresh air.
我去外面透透气
Thank you, I am very grateful to you.
谢谢 我很感激你
I am only returning a favor to your daughter.
我只是还你女儿人情而已
Take my daughter away from here, Kazuma.
和真 你带走我女儿吧
Please.
拜托了
I don't want to.
我才不要
What is the deal with this? Is it some kind of punishment game?
这是什么惩罚游戏吗
W-Why do you always act like this?
你…你这家伙为什么总是这样
What the heck?
搞什么啊
Looks like the kingdom's confidant has figured out what I am thinking.
王国的心腹好像看穿我的想法了
Understood.
知道了
I will take good care of her.
我会好好照顾她的
Lalatina.
拉拉蒂娜
Are you content with your current life?
现在的生活快乐吗
Yes.
是的
To the extent that I would be willing to sacrifice everything
快乐到我愿意抛弃一切
to protect my companions.
守护我的伙伴
I see.
这样啊
Father, I love you.
父亲大人 我爱你
Many thanks for seeing me through childhood and into maturity.
谢谢你抚养我长大成人
Once you feel better,
等你恢复健康后
go ahead and share stories about mom with me
再跟我说妈妈的事
until I drift off to sleep.
直到我入睡吧
It appears that you have regressed to a younger age.
你仿佛变回了小时候
Just for a little while… remain… in this state…
暂时…保持…这样…
Father.
父亲大人
He does not have much time left.
伯父所剩的时间…不多了
Sacred Break Spell.
Sacred Break Spell
Father!
父亲大人
This is a curse.
这是诅咒
You have been hit with quite a powerful curse.
伯父 你被下了厉害的诅咒
I effortlessly lifted it with my strength.
我用我的力量轻松帮你解开了
That'll be fine.
这样就没问题了
Darkness, that's really great.
达克妮丝 真是太好了
Mister, do not forget to tell her more about her mom.
伯父要多跟她说说妈妈的事哦
How beautiful.
真美好…
Useless demon!
没用的恶魔
So, is that all there is to your power
你那个操纵事理的力量
of manipulating reality?
就只有这点程度吗
It appears that the curse I cast upon Lord Dustiness
我对达斯堤尼斯卿下的诅咒
has been lifted.
好像被解开了
The curse has been lifted?
诅咒解开了?
That's not good.
不妙啊
If it goes on like this…
这样下去的话…
Max!
马克士
Help me come up with a clever excuse
这次也给我找个好借口
to bend reality this time.
扭曲真实吧
No can do, Aldarp.
没办法 阿尔达普
No can do?
没办法?
You useless demon.
你这个下级恶魔…
Do you not remember that I was the one who summoned you
你忘了自己是被我用这个神器
with this sacred treasure?
召唤出来的吗
Do it!
给我做
You have no right to refuse.
你没有拒绝的权利
Can't be helped.
没办法
The powerful light that breaks the curse is obstructing me.
解开诅咒的强光在妨碍我
So I can't do it.
所以我做不到
You useless thing.
你这个废物
I don't need a guy like you.
我不需要你这种家伙了
Here's the last command.
这是最后的命令
Bring Lalatina to me.
把拉拉蒂娜带来我面前
If you do so, I will pay the price.
那样的话我就付你代价
Pay the price?
付我代价?
Yes.
没错
If you bring Lalatina to me--
只要把拉拉蒂娜带来我面前…
My lord.
领主大人
I have come to apologize to you for today's incident.
我为今天的事来向你道歉
W-Well done, Max.
干…干得好 马克士
I will pay you the price as agreed.
我就依照约定付你代价
And then cancel the contract.
然后解除契约
-Contract… -Lalatina, Lalatina.
-契约… -拉拉蒂娜 拉拉蒂娜
My lord.
领主大人
I am willing to offer my own body in exchange
请用我的身体作为交换
for the life of my companions.
饶我伙伴一命
You are mine…
你是我的…
You are already mine.
你已经是我的了
So, did you think the person who showed up was Lalatina?
你以为是拉拉蒂娜吗
Unfortunately, it's me.
很遗憾 是我
Oh.
哎呀
Such stunning and powerful negative emotions.
真是惊人又强烈的负面情感
Truly delicious, truly delicious.
真美味 真美味
This eerie sensation…
这种毛骨悚然的感觉…
Just like Max.
跟马克士一样
Have I seen you somewhere?
我在哪里见过你吗
I have lost count of how many times I have introduced myself to you.
我不知道向你自我介绍过几千遍了
It is nice to meet you again.
那我这次也说一声幸会吧
Maxwell, a master of bending reality.
扭曲真实的马克士威尔
I am Vanir, the demon with the ability to see into the future.
我是预知未来的恶魔巴尼尔
Vanir?
巴尼尔…
Vanir.
巴尼尔
What is happening? I am feeling a wave of nostalgia.
怎么回事 我觉得好怀念
Let's go back to hell.
我们回地狱吧
Maxwell, the master of bending reality.
操纵事理的马克士威尔
That guy is my servant.
那家伙是我的仆人
Servant?
仆人?
Maxwell, a Duke of Hell much like me,
跟我同样是地狱公爵的马克士威尔
is your servant?
是你的仆人?
D-Duke?
公…爵?
You are fortunate.
你只是运气好而已
If you had summoned another demon,
要是召唤出别的恶魔
you would have definitely been ripped apart on the spot.
肯定会当场被碎尸万段
Vanir, Vanir.
巴尼尔 巴尼尔
You are where you are because of him.
你是多亏他才能得到现在的地位
Do not forget to express your gratitude to him.
好好感谢他
Pay the price as agreed.
依照约定付出代价吧
Then, terminate the contract.
然后解除契约
Exactly.
没错
The real issue lies in the contract between you and Maxwell.
你和马克士威尔之间的契约 才是问题
Gosh.
真是的
It was quite a hassle for no reason at all.
害我大费周章绕了一大圈
Could it be…
难道说…
You have got the right idea.
你想得没错
I am the one who discovered how to make that brat repay his debt
就是我想办法让那个小鬼还债
and informed him about you.
并把你的事告诉他
Very well.
很好很好
Such amazing negative emotions.
真是美好的负面情感
Truly delicious, truly delicious.
真美味 真美味
What? What did you say? Bastard!
什么 你说什么 混蛋
Okay, you are no longer needed.
好了 你已经没用处了
I will bring him back to hell,
我要带他回地狱
then return to toiling away under that useless manager.
然后回到那个废物店长的底下 苦命工作
Vanir, Vanir.
巴尼尔 巴尼尔
We must make sure Aldarp pays the price before we leave.
回去前必须让阿尔达普付出代价
Yeah, yeah.
知道了 知道了
I'll pay you the price, now please leave.
我就付你代价 快滚吧
It hurts! It hurts!
好痛 痛死了
Aldarp, Aldarp.
阿尔达普 阿尔达普
-What a wonderful scream, Aldarp. -Let me go, Maxwell!
-好棒的叫声 阿尔达普 -放开我 马克士
-Stop it, just stop!
-住手 快住手
The price you must pay is to give him
你要付出的代价
the negative emotions that he most enjoys.
是献上马克士威尔最爱的负面情感
The remaining years of your life are completely insufficient.
你所剩的寿命完全不够
In…
既…
In that case, sacrifice someone from your family?
既然这样 就牺牲家里的人?
Unfortunately,
很遗憾
we can only demand the price from the individual who signed the contract.
只能要求签约者付出代价
Although it is a really precious negative emotion,
虽然是很宝贵的负面情感
despair is not my preference.
但绝望的负面情感不是我的喜好
That negative emotion is…
那种负面情感…
Maxwell's favorite.
是马克士威尔最爱的滋味
The lord has disappeared?
领主失踪了?
For some reason, all the horrible things he did were revealed, and the one who
不知为何他做的坏事一一被发现了
delivered the sacred treasure that can exchange bodies to Princess Iris
把能交换身体的神器 送给爱丽丝殿下的人
appears to have been him as well.
好像也是他
I heard he went away since his wrongdoings were revealed.
听说他是因为东窗事发才逃走
It is the talk of the town.
大家议论纷纷
Seriously?
真的假的
You no longer have to run away at night.
你们不需要连夜潜逃了
See, I said nothing would happen.
看吧 我就说不会有事
Really.
真是的
I stayed up all night to prepare the bag. I'm exhausted.
亏我还熬夜准备 累死我了
In any case, we will sleep until the evening
总之我们先睡到傍晚
and then go to the guild for dinner.
再去公会吃晚餐吧
What's wrong with you?
你怎么了
Darkness?
达克妮丝?
Megumin, you don't know yet, do you?
惠惠还不知道吧
Kazuma bought Darkness.
达克妮丝被和真买下了哦
Is she too terrified to enter the house?
她是害怕到不敢进屋吧
Hey, watch your language.
喂 注意你的说法
No, Megumin.
不是的 惠惠
Not quite, while that is not inaccurate, it is not like that.
不对 虽然没错 但不是那样
I am sorry, I did something selfish.
对不起 我做了任性的事
I actually done something stupid.
我真的做了蠢事
I don't mind at all.
我一点也不在意哦
Although Kazuma lost a lot of stuff all at once,
虽然和真一下子失去很多东西
the end result is excellent.
但这种结果真是太好了
Yeah, yeah.
是啊是啊
Because of this,
而且我也因为这样
I discovered that your father has been cursed.
发现达克妮丝的爸爸被下诅咒
That money should be
那些钱
reimbursed with the lord's confiscated possessions.
应该会用领主被没收的财产弥补
However…
不过…
The intellectual property that Kazuma sold
和真卖掉的智慧财产
will never be reclaimed.
再也回不来了
So that was the reason?
原来是为了那种事啊
Don't worry about it.
别在意啦
After all, I've already learned cooking skills.
反正我已经学会烹饪技能
I can set up a stall…
可以摆摊…
Huh? Will I get my money back?
咦 钱会回来吗
Yes.
对
The two billion you advanced for me,
你帮我代垫的20亿
along with additional compensations.
和各种赔偿费
T-Two billion?
2…20亿?
I always feel that Mr. Kazuma is a bit…
总觉得和真先生有点那个呢
Yes, very much that.
对 非常那个
Huh?
诶
I want to make a nice tiny hut for Jelteman.
我也想帮爵尔帝盖一栋气派的小屋
That's right, it's exactly that feeling.
没错 的确是那种感觉
By the way, I want a new robe.
顺便说一下 我想要新的长袍
These annoying women…
这群臭女人
Listen up, I'm going to stay out for a week.
听好了 我要外宿一星期…
What's wrong? Didn't I say I don't mind?
怎么了 我不是说没关系了吗
Um… the letter I wrote…
那个…我写的那封信
I see.
原来如此
Does she think she is no longer a member of our team?
她以为自己不是队友了吗
What, that's--
什么嘛 那种事…
What are you talking about?
你在说什么啊
You are a vital cross knight on our team.
你是我们队里重要的十字骑士
I will surely not let you go.
我绝对不会放你走的
That's right.
对啊
What's the point of talking about it now?
事到如今还说什么啊
Are you an idiot?
你是笨蛋吗
Is not this the only place you belong?
你的归属只有这里吧
Hey, that's what I wanted to say.
喂 那是我本来想说的话
Um…
那…那个
I am a cross knight who is physically strong
我是只有身体强壮
but can't fence well.
却无法好好击剑的十字骑士
But is it possible
但是 能不能…
for me to join you again?
能不能再让我加入你们呢
Of course, you can.
当然可以啦
Welcome back.
欢迎回来
I…
我…
I'm back.
我回来了
I remember being joyful every day from the time
从和王女一起生活开始
I lived with the princess
经历队伍存亡的危机
until I experienced the team's survival dilemma
和吵吵闹闹的时光
and the raucous moments.
回想起来每天都很快乐
With friends on my side
有伙伴在
and reliable individuals all around.
还有推心置腹的人们
I dwell in this town,
我住在这个城镇
and perhaps I will journey with these teammates again
也许又会为了追求渺小的刺激
to seek modest pleasures.
和这些队友一起去冒险吧
In this wonderful world.
在这个美好的世界
Attempted?
未遂?
Hey, Kazuma.
喂 和真
You're not actually an idiot, are you?
你该不会真的是笨蛋吧
Weren't you going to bring Darkness back?
你不是去带达克妮丝回来的吗
Even though it was a night raid,
不…不过虽说是夜访
I was merely touched in the stomach.
但只摸了肚子
Night raid?
夜访?
Wait a second.
等一下
No, that's true.
不对 没错
Although that is true,
虽然是这样没错
did not you hold my hand yourself?
但是你自己握住我的手吧
Hold hand?
握手?
No, that's not it.
不…不是啦
I was thinking since I have to marry the lord anyway…
我是在想反正都要嫁给领主了…
Admitted!
承认了
Darkness admitted she had seduced him!
达克妮丝承认是自己引诱他了
I will not disturb you people,
我就不打扰你们
I am going to sun the Jelteman.
带爵尔帝的蛋去晒太阳了
How shameless can you be, Darkness?
达克妮丝你到底有多没节操啊
And here I was, worrying about you!
亏我这么担心你
Wait. H-Hold on.
等等 先…先等一下
Hey, Kazuma.
喂 和真
Explain it properly.
你好好解释一下
It can't be helped.
没办法
Hey, Aqua.
我说阿库娅
How does this country register marriages?
这个国家是怎么办理结婚登记的?
Why are you asking this so suddenly?
为什么突然问这个
To begin, on the morning of the wedding ceremony, file a marriage application
首先是在举行婚礼的早上
with government offices to become a married pair.
向政府机关提出 要成为夫妻的结婚申请
Then, at noon, hold the wedding ceremony…
然后中午举行结婚…典礼…
What caused you to suddenly freeze?
为什么突然愣住
It is becoming more common for people to go through a divorce these days.
最…最近离过婚 也不是什么稀奇的事了
It is clear she is a masochist and a virgin,
明明是大小姐却是被虐狂
but she is being divorced…
明明是处女却离过婚…
The man fled in stealth overnight.
对方连夜潜逃了
Does this indicate that people will believe Darkness has been abandoned?
这代表世人会以为 是达克妮丝被抛弃吗
Alright.
好啦
Do not stress about trivial stuff like marriage registration.
别在意结婚登记这种小事啦
Divorcedness.
离婚妮丝
Wha--
什…
Don't call me Divorcedness!
不准叫我离婚妮丝